♫ Man ammen toltha I dann hen morn?
(Who brings to us this token of darkness?)
I amar prestar aen.
Han mathon ne nen.
♫ Si danna atha nauva
(Now all will fall away)
Han mathon ne chae.
A han noston ned 'wilith.
♫ Nênâkham nêpâm abârat aglar
(We come grasp power and glory)
Tangado haid!
(Hold positions!)
Leithio i philinn!
(Fire the arrows!)
♫ Nêbâ Katharâd
(Deny Eternal Life)
♫ Nidir nênâ
(We are the Nine)
♫ Nêbâbîtham dâur
(We cling to the darkness)
♫ Nênâkham nêpâm abârat aglar
(We come grasp power and glory)
♫ Tercáno Nuruva
(The Herald of Death)
♫ Nêbâbîtham Magânanê
(We renounce our Maker)
♫ I tuo, i macil
(The strength, the weapon)
♫ Á lelyat túrenna!
(Go to victory!)
Zigur...
(Sauron...)
♫ Rîn athar annún-aearath
(O Queen beyond the Western Seas)
♫ Calad ammen i reniar
(O light to us that wander)
♫ Mi 'aladhremmin ennorath
(Amid the tree-woven lands of Middle-earth.)
♫ A Elbereth Gilthoniel
(Elbereth Star-kindler)
♫ I chin a thûl lín míriel...
(Your eyes and breath, like shining jewels...)
♫ Ash Burz-Durbagu burzum-ishi
(One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne)
♫ Daghburz-ishi
(In the land of Mordor)
♫ Makha gulshu darulu
(Where the shadows lie)
♫ Ash Burz-Durbagu burzum-ishi
(One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne)
Gulshu durbgu
(Lord of shadows)
♫ Nêpâm nêd
(We grasp for ourselves)
♫ Nêbâbîtham Magânanê
(We renounce our Maker)
♫ Bârî’n Katharâd
(Lords of Eternal Life)
♫ Nidir nênâ
(We are the Nine)
♫ Dâur-ad
(Darkness)
Nubin sherkuk
(I smell your blood)
...sherkuk
(...your blood)
♫ Bârî’n Katharâd
(Lords of Eternal Life)
♫ Îdô Nidir nênâ
(Now, we, the Nine)
♫ Kham nêpâm 'bârat aglar
(Come grasp power and glory)
Tinúviel elvanui
(Tinúviel the elven-fair)
Elleth alfirin ethelhael
(Immortal maiden elven-wise)
O hon ring finnil fuinui
(About him cast her night-dark hair)
A renc gelebrin thiliol.
(And arms like silver glimmering.)
♫ Bârî’n Katharâd
(Lords of Eternal Life)
♫ Îdô Nidir nênâ
(Now, we are the Nine)
♫ Nêpâm ned abârat
(We grasp power for ourselves)
♫ Nidir nênâkham
(We, the Nine, are coming)
♫ Nêbâbîtham Magânanê
(We renounce our Maker)
♫ Nêtabdam dâur
(We cling to the darkness)
Gûm-ishi...
(In the Void...)
...ashi...
(...only...)
...gurum
(...death)
Makha gulshu darulu
(Where the Shadows lie)
Daghburz-ishi makha gulshu darulu
(In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie)
♫ I ce
(The earth)
♫ I cemen nurrua
(The earth groans)
♫ Ar i sure...
(And the wind...)
♫ ...i súre...
(...the wind...)
♫ ...naina.
(...is crying.)
♫ Tinúviel el vanui
(Tinúviel, the elven-fair)
♫ Elleth alfirin
(Immortal maiden)
Im Arwen - Telin le thaed.
(I am Arwen - I’ve come to help you.)
Lasto beth nîn, tolo dan na ngalad.
(Hear my voice, come back to the light.)
Dartho guin Berian. Rych le ad tolthathon.
(Stay with the hobbits, I’ll send horses for you.)
Hon mabathon. Rochon ellint im.
(I will take him. I am the swifter rider.)
Andelu i ven.
(The road is very dangerous.)
Frodo fîr. Ae athradon i hîr...
(Frodo dies. If I get across the river...)
...tûr gwaith nîn beriatha hon.
(...the power of my people will protect him.)
Be iest lîn.
(As you wish.)
Noro lim, Asfaloth. Noro lim!
(Ride fast, Asfaloth. Ride fast!)
♫ Bârî’n Katharâd
(Lords of Eternal Life)
♫ Îdô kham nêpâm
(Now we come grasp)
Noro lim, Asfaloth!
(Ride fast, Asfaloth!)
♫ Nênâkham nêpâm
(We come grasp)
♫ 'bârat aglar
(power, glory)
♫ Nêbâ Katharâd
(Deny Eternal Life)
♫ Nidir nênâ
(We are the Nine)
♫ Nêbâbîtham dâur
(We cling to the darkness)
Nîn o Chithaeglir...
(Waters of the Misty Mountains...)
...lasto beth daer;
(...listen to the great word;)
Rimmo nˆn Bruinen dan in Ulaer.
(flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths.)
Nîn o Chithaeglir...
(Waters of the Misty Mountains...)
...lasto beth daer;
(...listen to the great word;)
Rimmo nˆn Bruinen dan in Ulaer!
(flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths!)
♫ What grace is given me
♫ Let it pass to him
♫ Let him be spared
♫ Mighty Valar, save him
Lasto beth nîn... tolo dan na ngalad.
(Hear my voice... come back to the light.)
♫ I ce
(The earth)
♫ A, Elbereth Gilthoniel
(O, Elbereth Kindler of Stars)
♫ silivren penna míriel
(Glittering light falling like shining jewels)
♫ A El'
(O, the Stars)
♫ A, Elbereth Gil[thoniel]
(O, Elbereth Kindler of Stars)
A si i-Dhuath ú-orthor, Aragorn.
(Till now the Shadow not masters, Aragorn)
Ú or le a ú or nin.
(Not over you, not over me.)
♫ O môr henion i dhû
(From darkness I understand the night)
Renich i lú i erui govannem?
(Do you remember when we first met?)
♫ Ely siriar, êl sila
(Dreams flow, a star shines)
Nauthannen i ned ôl reniannen.
(I thought I had strayed into a dream.)
Gwenwin in enninath.
(Long years have passed.)
♫ Ai! Aníron Undómiel
(Ah! I desire Evenstar)
Ú-’arnech in naeth i si celich.
(You did not wear the troubles you carry now.)
Renech i beth i pennen?
(Do you remember what I told you?)
♫ Tiro! El eria e môr
(Look! A star rises out of darkness)
♫ I ‘lîr en êl luitha ‘úren
(The song of the star enchants my heart)
♫ Ai! Aníron...
(Ah! I desire...)
Sherkuk-ishi
(In your blood)
[Gandalf] Ash nazg durbatulûk
(One ring to rule them all)
[Sauron] Shre nazg golugranu kilmi-nudu
(Three Rings for the Elven-kings under the sky)
[Gandalf] Ash nazg gimbatul
(One ring to find them)
[Sauron] Ombi kuzd-durbagu... sherkuk
(Seven for the Dwarf-lords... blood)
[Gandalf] Ash nazg thrakatuluk
(One ring to bring them all)
[Sauron] Ash burz durbagu burzum-ishi
(One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne)
[Gandalf] Agh burzum-ishi krimpatul.
(and in the darkness bind them.)
Havo dad, Legolas.
(Sit down, Legolas.)
...Daghburz-ishi makha gulshu... sherkuk
...In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows... blood
[Daghburz]-ishi makha gulshu darulu
In the Land of Mordor where the Shadows lie
Ash nazg durbatuluk...
(One ring to rule them all...)
Ash nazg gimbatul...
(One ring to find them...)
Ash nazg durbatuluk...
(One ring to rule them all...)
Ash nazg gimbatul...
(One ring to find them...)
Ash nazg durbatuluk...
(One ring to rule them all...)
Ash nazg gimbatul...
(One ring to find them...)
Ash nazg durbatuluk...
(One ring to rule them all...)
♫ Estel le iôn adar lín
(You are your father’s son)
♫ Û iôn naneth lín
(Not your mother’s child)
Anirne hene beriad i chen lîn.
(She wanted to protect her child.)
♫ A chéneg a ionneg
(Little boy, little one)
Ned Imladris nauthant e le beriathar aen.
(She thought in Rivendell you would be safe.)
♫ Danna si (fuin)
(Night is falling)
♫ Tolo na rengy
(Come into my arms)
♫ Ne theilien
(Slaying demons in the shadows)
♫ Uilos le linnathon
(I will sing to you)
♫ Nef aear sî nef aearon
(Beyond the Sea, beyond the wide and sundering Sea)
♫ I tuo I macil staldaron
(The strength, the weapon, the needs of the valiant)
♫ Marinyë túren
(The mean of victory)
Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
(Wake up cruel Redhorn!)
Nai yarvaxëa rasselya!
(May your horn be bloodstained!)
Losto Caradhras, sedho, hodo, nuitho i ’ruith!
(Sleep Caradhras, be still, lie still, hold your wrath!)
Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
(Wake up cruel Redhorn!)
Nai yarvaxëa rasselya...
(May your bloodstained horn...)
...taltuva ñotto-carinnar!
(...fall upon the enemy-heads!)
Ithildin.
(“moon-star”)
♫ Man ammen toltha
(Who brings this?)
♫ Si danna atha
(All will fall away)
Annon Edhellen, edro hi ammen!
(Gate of the elves, open now for me!)
Fennas Nogothrim...
(Doorway of the dwarf-folk...)
lasto beth lammen.
(listen to the word of my tongue.)
Ando Eldarinwa...
(Gate of elves...)
a lasta quettanya...
(listen to my word...)
Fenda Casarinwa!
(threshold of dwarves!)
Fennas Nogothrim...
(Doorway of the dwarf-folk...)
Mellon.
♫ Durin ku bin-amrad
(Durin who is Deathless)
♫ Ugmal sullu addad
(Eldest of all Fathers)
♫ Ku bakana
(Beneath the mountain)
♫ Ana aznân...
(Who awoke...)
♫ ...undu abad
(...to darkness)
♫ Ku ganaga
(Who walked alone)
♫ Tur ganâd abanul
(Through halls of stone)
♫ Durin ku bin-amrad
(Durin who is Deathless)
♫ Urkhas tanakhi!
(The demon comes!)
♫ Kamin takalladi!
(The earth shakes!)
♫ Ugrud tashniki kurduma!
(Fear rips our heart!)
♫ Urus ni buzra! Urkhas tanakhi! Lu! Lu! Lu! Lu!
(Fire in the deep! The demon comes! No! No! No! No!)
♫ Urkhas tanakhi! Urus ni buzra!
(The demon comes! Fire in the deep!)
♫ Arrâs talbabi, fillumâ, fillumâ!
(Flames lick, our skin, our skin!)
♫ Ugrûd tashniki, kurdumâ, kurdumâ!
(Fear rips, our heart, our heart!)
♫ Urus urkhas, urkhas tanakhi! Urkhas tanakhi!
(Demon of fire, the demon comes, the demon comes!)
♫ Kâmin takalladi! Askad gabil urus!
(The earth shakes! A great shadow of fire!)
♫ Urkhas tanakhi! Urkhas tanakhi!
(The demon comes! The demon comes!)
♫ Ugrûd tashniki kurdumâ!
(Fear rips our heart!)
♫ Urkhas! Urus!
(Demon! Fire!)
♫ Urus ni buzra! Urkhas tanakhi! Lu! Lu! Lu! Lu!
(Fire in the deep! The demon comes! No! No! No! No!)
♫ Man ammen toltha I dann hen môrn?
(Who brings to us this token of darkness?)
♫ Si danna atha nauva
(Now all will fall away)
♫ Mel, melmë nóren sina
(Love, our love for this land)
♫ Nur ala aearon nur
(is deeper than the depths of the sea)
Mae govannen, Legolas Thranduilion.
(Well met, Legolas son of Thranduil.)
Govannas vîn gwennen le,
(Our fellowship stands in your debt,)
Haldir o Lórien.
(Haldir of Lórien.)
A, Aragorn in Dúnedain...
(Oh, Aragorn of the Dúnedain...)
istannen le ammen.
(you are known to us.)
Haldir.
Îsh kakhfê ai-dûr-rugnul!
(May my excrement be poured upon the naked-jawed!)
Boe ammen veriad lîn. Andelu i ven.
(We need your protection. The road is very dangerous.)
Merin le telim.
(I wish we may come with you.)
Henio, aníron boe ammen i dulu lîn!
(Please, understand, we need your support!)
Merin le telim.
(I wish we may come with you.)
Andelu i ven.
(The road is very dangerous.)
♫ Ela i cá[le]!
(Behold the light!)
♫ Nenya sina
(Nenya is this)
♫ Corma úhátima
(unbreakable Ring)
♫ I haryanye
(That I possess)
♫ In gwidh ristennin,
(The bonds cut)
♫ Ilfirin nairelma
(Undying is our regret)
♫ I fae narchannen
(The spirit broken)
♫ Nauva i nauva
(what should be shall be)
♫ I Lach Anor ed
(The Flame of Anor)
♫ Ilfirin nairelma
(Undying is our regret)
♫ ardhon gwannen
(has left this World)
♫ Ar ullume nucuvalme
(and yet we will cast all away)
♫ Mithrandir A Randir Vithren!
(Mithrandir, O Pilgrim Grey!)
♫ Nauva i nauva
(What should be shall be)
♫ Ú-reniathach
(No more you will)
♫ Nauva i nauva
(What should be shall be)
♫ I amar galen
(Wander the green fields of this earth)
♫ I reniad lín ne môr
(Your journey has ended in darkness)
♫ melme nóren
(our love for this land)
♫ nuithannen
(in darknes.)
♫ sina nairelma
(is our regret)
♫ Si danna atha nauva
(Now all will fall away)
♫ Melmelma nóren sina
(Our love for this land)
♫ Núra [lá] earo núri
(is deeper than the depths of the sea)
♫ Ilfirin nairelma
(Undying is our regret)
♫ I nairelma nauva
(Our regret will be)
♫ Núra [lá] earo
(deeper than the deeps of the sea)
♫ Ai! Laurië lantar lassi súrinen
(Ah! Like gold fall the leaves in the wind)
♫ Yéni únótimë...
(Numberless long years...)
Le aphadar aen.
(You are being followed.)
♫ [Súri]nen yéni únótimë ve rámar aldaron!
(Numberless long years as the wings of trees!)
♫ Yéni ve lintë yuldar avánier
(The long years have passed like swift draughts)
♫ mi oromardi lissë-miruvóreva
(of the sweet mead in lofty halls)
Am meleth dîn...
(For her love...)
I ant e guil Arwen Undómiel pígatha.
(The gift of life of Arwen will dwindle.)
Aníron i e broniatha, ad ae periatham...
(I wish that she endures, even if we separate...)
athar i methid en-amar hen.
(beyond the limits of this world.)
Aníron i e círatha na Valannor.
(I wish that she sails to Valinor.)
Namárië.
(Farewell.)
Nadath nâ i moe cerich.
(There is much you have yet to do.)
Dan, ú-'eveditham, Elessar.
(We shall not meet again, Elessar.)
♫ Namárië! Nai hiruvalyë Valimar!
(Farewell! Maybe thou shalt find Valimar!)
♫ Namá[rië]!
(Farewell!)
♫ Et Eärello Endorenna utúlien
(Out of the Great Sea to Middle-earth I come)
♫ Sinomë maruvan ar Hildinyar
(In this place I will abide, and my heirs)
Gûm-ishi...
(In the void...)
...ashi...
(...only...)
...gurum
(...death)
Akha gûm-ishi ashi gurum
(Here in the void, only death)
♫ I tuo i macil a staldaron
(The strength, the weapon, the needs of the valiant)
♫ Marinyë Cor[ma]
(Let the Ring be your weapon)
♫ I tuo i macil a lelyat túrenna
(The strength, the weapon, go to victory!)
♫ Ash Burz-Durbagu burzum-ishi
(One for the Dark Lord on his dark throne)
♫ Ú-velin i vegil an aegas
(I do not love the bright sword for its sharpness)
♫ Egor i... bilin a linn[as]
(Nor the... arrow for its swiftness)
♫ I alda helda, i ehtelë lína
(The tree is bare, the fountain still)
♫ Manna lelyalye Voromírë?
(Whither goest thou Boromir?)
♫ Cánalya desse sí mas[së]
(We heard your call but cannot find you)
♫ Ú-velin i ve[gil]
(I do not love the bright sword)
♫ Shines down upon you
♫ May it be when darkness falls
♫ Your heart will be true
♫ You walk a lonely road
♫ Oh! How far you are from home
♫ Mornie utúlië
(Darkness has come)
♫ Believe and you will find your way
♫ Mornie alantië
(Darkness has fallen)
♫ A promise lives within you now
♫ May it be the shadow's call
♫ Will fly away
♫ May it be you journey on
♫ To light the day
♫ When the night is overcome
♫ You may rise to find the sun
♫ Mornie utúlië
(Darkness has come)
♫ Believe and you will find your way
♫ Mornie alantië
(Darkness has fallen)
♫ A promise lives within you now
♫ A promise lives within you...
♫ ...now
♫ When the cold of winter comes
♫ Starless night will cover day
♫ In the veiling of the sun
♫ We will walk in bitter rain
♫ But in dreams
♫ I can hear your name
♫ And in dreams
♫ We will meet again
♫ When the seas and mountains fall
♫ And we come, to end of days
♫ In the dark I hear a call
♫ Calling me there
♫ I will go there
♫ And back again.
♫ A, Elbereth Gilthoniel
(O, Elbereth Kindler of Stars)
♫ silivren penna míriel
(Glittering light falling like shining jewels)